coinjar.com 2018-11-11

# Privacy & Cookies - CoinJar

* * *

## Cookies

CoinJar uses Google Analytics, Cloudflare and our own cookies to help deliver high quality, reliable and secure products to our customers.

These include:

  * Anonymous site performance cookies;
  * Anonymous analytics cookies;
  * Geotargetting cookies (Cloudflare);
  * Registration cookies.

For more information about how we use cookies, email us at

* * *

## Privacy

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which CoinJar collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User") of the coinjar.com website and its subdomains ("Site"). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by CoinJar.

## Personal identification information

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our Site, register on our Site, place an order, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, phone number. Users intending to use certain services may be asked for, as appropriate, residential address, date of birth, nationality, gender, identity documentation, and relevant bank and payment card information. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities. We may collect additional information you may disclose to our customer support team.

## Non-personal identification information

We may collect non-personal identification information about a User whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include technical information about the User’s means of connection to our Site, such as details of the User’s browser, computer operating system, smartphone, the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

## Web browser cookies

Our Site may use "cookies" to enhance User’s experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being used. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.

## How we use collected information

CoinJar may collect and use Users’ personal information for the following purposes:

  * To improve customer service - Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * To process payments - We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.
  * To send periodic emails - We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If a User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time a User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site.
  * To fulfil compliance requirements - We may use the information Users provide in order to ensure that regulated companies which work with us are able to fulfil their obligations under legislation relating to money laundering, terrorist financing, and other forms of financial compliance. We only share this information with outside parties to the extent necessary to provide the service.

## How we protect your information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored and processed via our Site.

Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures. We store your personal and non-personal information securely throughout the life of your CoinJar account on our computers in Australia and elsewhere in the world where CoinJar facilities or our service providers are located. CoinJar will retain your personal information for a minimum of five years or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations or resolve disputes.

Payment card data is securely transferred and hosted off-site by a payment partner in compliance with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI DSS). This information is not accessible to CoinJar staff.

## Sharing your personal information

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users’ personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above.

We may share your personal information with:

  * Financial institutions, payment processors, and identity service providers with which we operate.
  * Service providers under contract who help with parts of our business operations such as fraud prevention, compliance, marketing, and technology services. Our contracts dictate that these service providers only use your information in connection with the services they perform for us and not for their own benefit.
  * Law enforcement, government officials, or other third parties when:
    * We are compelled to do so by a subpoena, court order, or similar legal procedure; or
    * We believe in good faith that the disclosure of personal information is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss, to report suspected illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our User Agreement.
    * Other third parties with your consent or direction to do so.

Before CoinJar shares your information with any third party that is not acting as an agent to perform tasks on behalf of and under the instructions of CoinJar, CoinJar will first ensure that the third party either is subject to the European Union’s Directive on Data Protection, or is subject to data protection rules of a territory on the European Commission's list of territories deemed to have an adequate level of protection, or enters into a written agreement with CoinJar requiring that the third party will provide at least the same level of privacy as required by

## Third party websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies.

## Deactivating your account

If you deactivate your CoinJar account, we will mark your account in our database as "Deactivated," but will keep your account information in our database for a period of time described above. This is necessary in order to deter fraud, by ensuring that persons who try to commit fraud will not be able to avoid detection simply by closing their account and opening a new account. If you do deactivate your account, your personally identifiable information will not be used by us for any further purposes, nor sold or shared with third parties, except as necessary to prevent fraud and assist law enforcement, as required by law, or in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Compliance with children’s online privacy protection act

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our Site from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

## Changes to this privacy policy

CoinJar has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

## Your acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

## Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at

[support@coinjar.com](mailto:support@coinjar.com). Alternative contact options include:

## Addresses

 **CoinJar UK Limited (Headquarters)**  
71-75 Shelton Street  
Covent Garden  
London WC2H 9JQ  
United Kingdom **CoinJar Pty Ltd (Australia Office)**  
PO Box 116  
Collins St West, VIC, 8007  
Australia  

This document was last updated on 10 April, 2015

* * *
